Planning, Director of; Records ua020
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Director of Planning Records1974-1981
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Director of Planning
ua020
1.66
Records of the Director of Planning, a position that reported to the President and was responsible for coordinating the three-year and master planning process across the University.
Access
Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
The Director of Planning, also referred to as an Assistant to the President, coordinated with academic departments and the State Education Department to create departmental three-year plans and to prepare the campus-wide master plan.
This collection pertains mostly to the tenure of Nan Lin, a sociology professor who held the position of Acting Director from 1977-1978. He oversaw the development of many new academic programs on campus during his time as Director.
Scope and Contents
The contents of this collection relate to the development of three-year plans and master plans for administrative and academic departments. Materials include: correspondence with the State Education Department, correspondence with academic and administrative departments, and three-year planning documentation, and supporting material for the campus master plan.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection is arranged in the order it was received in.
Educational planning; Universities and colleges--planning; Education, Higher--Administration; Administrative records; UAlbany Presidential Offices; State University of New York at Albany. Office of the President; State University of New York at Albany
- Finance of Business, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Center For Government Reserve & Serv., Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Graduate Studies, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Atmospheric Science Research Center, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- College of General Studies, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- School of Education, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Criminal Justice, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Revised Three Year Plan School of Social Welfare, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Revision of Three-Year Plan College of Science & Mathematics, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Social & Behavioral Sciences, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- University Affairs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Capital District Data, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- SUNY Centers- State Trends, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- SUNY-A foreign Students, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "Basic Guidelines", 1974 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Attach. A - Campus Enroll - '72 Plan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Attach. B - Off plan. SVCS. Projections, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Attach C - SUNY Projects to '95, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Attach D Albany & Campus Capacity, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Attach F - Enrollment '73-4 to '75-76, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Attach G- H.S. Grads- And H Geog Orientation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- SED DATA- Incl. Albany- From SUNY, 1975 February (Box 1, Folder 22)
- 1972 Albany " Prospectus", Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- 1968 Albany M. Plan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
- SED DATA - (U.C.R. Projections to 1990), 1974 December-1975 January (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Report to Long-Range Planning Comm., Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- SUNY - "What's Ahead", 1975 October (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Call for Participation & Repsonses, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- M. Plan Corresp. - External + Internal, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Physical Plant -M Plan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
- President's Report, 1978 May (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Office of Planning [?] (Conference Agenda), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Correspondence on Planning Of Campus, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Correspondence, Memos to and From Business of Finance, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Correspondence with University Affairs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Higher Education Trends in New York State, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence with Dwight Smith, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, On-Campus Planning Activities, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- SED Reviews, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Complete- Graduate Students, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Admissions Activities, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with SUNY Central, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Division of Budget, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Certificate in Policy Planning & Analysis, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Center For Writing, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Education Proposal, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Criminal Justice Proposal, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Graduate School of Public Affairs Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Nursing Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- College of General Studies Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- School of Social Welfare Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Finance and Business Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Planning and Information Systems Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Computing Center Three-Year Devlopment Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Department Planning Formats, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Three-Year Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- EPC Review of Development Plans (Spring 1977) (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Abstracts (general), Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- College of Social & Behavioral Sciences Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- School of Business Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- College of Humanities & Fine Arts Three-Year Development Plan, 1977-1978; 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- College of Science & Mathematics Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- School of Library & Information Science Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- School of Criminal Justice Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- School of Education Three-Year Development Plan, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Planning Director, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)